var words = 
[
    {
        "question": "وَأَخَّرَتْ",
        "answer": "and left behind",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "wa-akharat",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلِمَتْ نَفْسٌ مَا قَدَّمَتْ وَأَخَّرَتْ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَخَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to delay, to give respite",
        "waznTlit": "akhara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذَا",
        "answer": "When",
        "pcklId": "373",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا السَّمَاءُ انْفَطَرَتْ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَإِذَا",
        "answer": "And when",
        "pcklId": "374",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "wa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا الْكَوَاكِبُ انْتَثَرَتْ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَإِذَا",
        "answer": "And when",
        "pcklId": "375",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "wa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا الْبِحَارُ فُجِّرَتْ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَإِذَا",
        "answer": "And when",
        "pcklId": "376",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "wa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا الْقُبُورُ بُعْثِرَتْ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِي",
        "answer": "Who",
        "pcklId": "1400",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي خَلَقَكَ فَسَوَّاكَ فَعَدَلَكَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلَّهِ",
        "answer": "(will be) with Allah",
        "pcklId": "2827",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "lillahi",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ لَا تَمْلِكُ نَفْسٌ لِنَفْسٍ شَيْئًا وَالْأَمْرُ يَوْمَئِذٍ لِلَّهِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْأَمْرُ",
        "answer": "and the Command",
        "pcklId": "244",
        "rootWordId": 69,
        "tlit": "wal-amru",
        "frequency": "248",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ لَا تَمْلِكُ نَفْسٌ لِنَفْسٍ شَيْئًا وَالْأَمْرُ يَوْمَئِذٍ لِلَّهِ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمْر",
        "waznEnglish": "command, affair, matter",
        "waznTlit": "amr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْإِنْسَانُ",
        "answer": "man",
        "pcklId": "82",
        "rootWordId": 78,
        "tlit": "l-insānu",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " يَا أَيُّهَا الْإِنْسَانُ مَا غَرَّكَ بِرَبِّكَ الْكَرِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنسَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you perceive",
        "waznTlit": "insān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْبِحَارُ",
        "answer": "the seas",
        "pcklId": "40",
        "rootWordId": 99,
        "tlit": "l-biḥāru",
        "frequency": "42",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا الْبِحَارُ فُجِّرَتْ",
        "rootWord": "ب ح ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَحْر",
        "waznEnglish": "the sea",
        "waznTlit": "baḥr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَبْرَارَ",
        "answer": "the righteous",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 114,
        "tlit": "l-abrāra",
        "frequency": "32",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْأَبْرَارَ لَفِي نَعِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ب ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَرّ",
        "waznEnglish": "you do good",
        "waznTlit": "barr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بُعْثِرَتْ",
        "answer": "are overturned",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 138,
        "tlit": "buʿ'thirat",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا الْقُبُورُ بُعْثِرَتْ",
        "rootWord": "ب ع ث ر",
        "rootWordType": "quadriliteral root",
        "wazn": "ب ع ث ر",
        "waznEnglish": "to overturn, to scatter",
        "waznTlit": "bā ʿayn thā rā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَحِيمٍ",
        "answer": "Hellfire",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 227,
        "tlit": "jaḥīmin",
        "frequency": "26",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ الْفُجَّارَ لَفِي جَحِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ج ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ح م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the blazing Fire",
        "waznTlit": "jīm ḥā mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَحَافِظِينَ",
        "answer": "(are) surely guardians",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 339,
        "tlit": "laḥāfiẓīna",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ عَلَيْكُمْ لَحَافِظِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ف ظ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَٰفِظ",
        "waznEnglish": "(orders) them to guard",
        "waznTlit": "ḥāfiẓ",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقَكَ",
        "answer": "created you",
        "pcklId": "172",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqaka",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي خَلَقَكَ فَسَوَّاكَ فَعَدَلَكَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَدْرَاكَ",
        "answer": "can make you know",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 469,
        "tlit": "adrāka",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَدْرَاكَ مَا يَوْمُ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "د ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَدْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make known",
        "waznTlit": "adrā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَدْرَاكَ",
        "answer": "can make you know",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 469,
        "tlit": "adrāka",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ مَا أَدْرَاكَ مَا يَوْمُ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "د ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَدْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make known",
        "waznTlit": "adrā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالدِّينِ",
        "answer": "the Judgment",
        "pcklId": "82",
        "rootWordId": 498,
        "tlit": "bil-dīni",
        "frequency": "101",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا بَلْ تُكَذِّبُونَ بِالدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "د ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they acknowledge",
        "waznTlit": "dīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الدِّينِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Judgment",
        "pcklId": "83",
        "rootWordId": 498,
        "tlit": "l-dīni",
        "frequency": "101",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يَصْلَوْنَهَا يَوْمَ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "د ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they acknowledge",
        "waznTlit": "dīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الدِّينِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Judgment",
        "pcklId": "84",
        "rootWordId": 498,
        "tlit": "l-dīni",
        "frequency": "101",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَدْرَاكَ مَا يَوْمُ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "د ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they acknowledge",
        "waznTlit": "dīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الدِّينِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Judgment",
        "pcklId": "85",
        "rootWordId": 498,
        "tlit": "l-dīni",
        "frequency": "101",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ مَا أَدْرَاكَ مَا يَوْمُ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "د ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they acknowledge",
        "waznTlit": "dīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِرَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "concerning your Lord",
        "pcklId": "936",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "birabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " يَا أَيُّهَا الْإِنْسَانُ مَا غَرَّكَ بِرَبِّكَ الْكَرِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَكَّبَكَ",
        "answer": "He assembled you",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 580,
        "tlit": "rakkabaka",
        "frequency": "15",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي أَيِّ صُورَةٍ مَا شَاءَ رَكَّبَكَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ك ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَكَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to assemble",
        "waznTlit": "rakkaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاءُ",
        "answer": "the sky",
        "pcklId": "349",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāu",
        "frequency": "381",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا السَّمَاءُ انْفَطَرَتْ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَسَوَّاكَ",
        "answer": "then fashioned you",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 747,
        "tlit": "fasawwāka",
        "frequency": "83",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي خَلَقَكَ فَسَوَّاكَ فَعَدَلَكَ",
        "rootWord": "س و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَوَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to fashion, to proportion",
        "waznTlit": "sawwā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَاءَ",
        "answer": "He willed",
        "pcklId": "234",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shāa",
        "frequency": "519",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي أَيِّ صُورَةٍ مَا شَاءَ رَكَّبَكَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَآءَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to will, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "shāa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَيْئًا",
        "answer": "anything",
        "pcklId": "517",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shayan",
        "frequency": "519",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ لَا تَمْلِكُ نَفْسٌ لِنَفْسٍ شَيْئًا وَالْأَمْرُ يَوْمَئِذٍ لِلَّهِ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَىْء",
        "waznEnglish": "had willed",
        "waznTlit": "shay",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَصْلَوْنَهَا",
        "answer": "They will burn (in) it",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 858,
        "tlit": "yaṣlawnahā",
        "frequency": "25",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَصْلَوْنَهَا يَوْمَ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَصْلَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to burn",
        "waznTlit": "yaṣlā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "صُورَةٍ",
        "answer": "form",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 869,
        "tlit": "ṣūratin",
        "frequency": "19",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي أَيِّ صُورَةٍ مَا شَاءَ رَكَّبَكَ",
        "rootWord": "ص و ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صُورَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and incline them",
        "waznTlit": "ṣūrat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَعَدَلَكَ",
        "answer": "then balanced you",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 966,
        "tlit": "faʿadalaka",
        "frequency": "28",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي خَلَقَكَ فَسَوَّاكَ فَعَدَلَكَ",
        "rootWord": "ع د ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَدَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be just",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَلِمَتْ",
        "answer": "Will know",
        "pcklId": "373",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "ʿalimat",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلِمَتْ نَفْسٌ مَا قَدَّمَتْ وَأَخَّرَتْ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "answer": "They know",
        "pcklId": "374",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "yaʿlamūna",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَعْلَمُونَ مَا تَفْعَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "غَرَّكَ",
        "answer": "has deceived you",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 1055,
        "tlit": "gharraka",
        "frequency": "27",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " يَا أَيُّهَا الْإِنْسَانُ مَا غَرَّكَ بِرَبِّكَ الْكَرِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "غ ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَرَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deceive, to delude",
        "waznTlit": "gharra",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِغَائِبِينَ",
        "answer": "(will be) absent",
        "pcklId": "58",
        "rootWordId": 1093,
        "tlit": "bighāibīna",
        "frequency": "60",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا هُمْ عَنْهَا بِغَائِبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ي ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَآئِبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "backbite",
        "waznTlit": "ghāibīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "فُجِّرَتْ",
        "answer": "are made to gush forth",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 1108,
        "tlit": "fujjirat",
        "frequency": "24",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا الْبِحَارُ فُجِّرَتْ",
        "rootWord": "ف ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فُجِّرَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cause gush",
        "waznTlit": "fujjirat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْفُجَّارَ",
        "answer": "the wicked",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1108,
        "tlit": "l-fujāra",
        "frequency": "24",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ الْفُجَّارَ لَفِي جَحِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ف ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فُجَّار",
        "waznEnglish": "you cause to gush forth",
        "waznTlit": "fujjār",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "انْفَطَرَتْ",
        "answer": "(is) cleft asunder",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 1141,
        "tlit": "infaṭarat",
        "frequency": "20",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا السَّمَاءُ انْفَطَرَتْ",
        "rootWord": "ف ط ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱنفَطَرَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be cleft asunder",
        "waznTlit": "infaṭarat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَفْعَلُونَ",
        "answer": "you do",
        "pcklId": "83",
        "rootWordId": 1143,
        "tlit": "tafʿalūna",
        "frequency": "108",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يَعْلَمُونَ مَا تَفْعَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to do",
        "waznTlit": "faʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْقُبُورُ",
        "answer": "the graves",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1171,
        "tlit": "l-qubūru",
        "frequency": "8",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا الْقُبُورُ بُعْثِرَتْ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَبْر",
        "waznEnglish": "and provides a grave for him",
        "waznTlit": "qabr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَدَّمَتْ",
        "answer": "it has sent forth",
        "pcklId": "27",
        "rootWordId": 1183,
        "tlit": "qaddamat",
        "frequency": "48",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلِمَتْ نَفْسٌ مَا قَدَّمَتْ وَأَخَّرَتْ",
        "rootWord": "ق د م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَدَّمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send forth, to offer",
        "waznTlit": "qaddama",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَاتِبِينَ",
        "answer": "recording",
        "pcklId": "317",
        "rootWordId": 1256,
        "tlit": "kātibīna",
        "frequency": "319",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كِرَامًا كَاتِبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ت ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَاتِب",
        "waznEnglish": "write",
        "waznTlit": "kātib",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "answer": "you deny",
        "pcklId": "175",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "tukadhibūna",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا بَلْ تُكَذِّبُونَ بِالدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكَرِيمِ",
        "answer": "the Most Noble",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 1267,
        "tlit": "l-karīmi",
        "frequency": "47",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " يَا أَيُّهَا الْإِنْسَانُ مَا غَرَّكَ بِرَبِّكَ الْكَرِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَرِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "You have honored",
        "waznTlit": "karīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كِرَامًا",
        "answer": "Noble",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 1267,
        "tlit": "kirāman",
        "frequency": "47",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " كِرَامًا كَاتِبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَرِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "You have honored",
        "waznTlit": "karīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكَوَاكِبُ",
        "answer": "the stars",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1304,
        "tlit": "l-kawākibu",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا الْكَوَاكِبُ انْتَثَرَتْ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ك ب",
        "rootWordType": "quadriliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك و ك ب",
        "waznEnglish": "a star",
        "waznTlit": "kāf wāw kāf bā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَمْلِكُ",
        "answer": "will have power",
        "pcklId": "43",
        "rootWordId": 1415,
        "tlit": "tamliku",
        "frequency": "206",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ لَا تَمْلِكُ نَفْسٌ لِنَفْسٍ شَيْئًا وَالْأَمْرُ يَوْمَئِذٍ لِلَّهِ",
        "rootWord": "م ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَلَكَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to possess, to have power",
        "waznTlit": "malakat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "انْتَثَرَتْ",
        "answer": "scatter",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1441,
        "tlit": "intatharat",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا الْكَوَاكِبُ انْتَثَرَتْ",
        "rootWord": "ن ث ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱنتَثَرَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to scatter",
        "waznTlit": "intatharat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَعِيمٍ",
        "answer": "bliss",
        "pcklId": "135",
        "rootWordId": 1492,
        "tlit": "naʿīmin",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْأَبْرَارَ لَفِي نَعِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَعِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "then good",
        "waznTlit": "naʿīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَفْسٌ",
        "answer": "a soul",
        "pcklId": "291",
        "rootWordId": 1500,
        "tlit": "nafsun",
        "frequency": "298",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلِمَتْ نَفْسٌ مَا قَدَّمَتْ وَأَخَّرَتْ",
        "rootWord": "ن ف س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَفْس",
        "waznEnglish": "self, soul, person, mind",
        "waznTlit": "nafs",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَفْسٌ",
        "answer": "a soul",
        "pcklId": "292",
        "rootWordId": 1500,
        "tlit": "nafsun",
        "frequency": "298",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ لَا تَمْلِكُ نَفْسٌ",
        "rootWord": "ن ف س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَفْس",
        "waznEnglish": "self, soul, person, mind",
        "waznTlit": "nafs",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِنَفْسٍ",
        "answer": "for a soul",
        "pcklId": "293",
        "rootWordId": 1500,
        "tlit": "linafsin",
        "frequency": "298",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " لِنَفْسٍ شَيْئًا وَالْأَمْرُ يَوْمَئِذٍ لِلَّهِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ف س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَفْس",
        "waznEnglish": "self, soul, person, mind",
        "waznTlit": "nafs",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمُ",
        "answer": "(is the) Day",
        "pcklId": "318",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmu",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَدْرَاكَ مَا يَوْمُ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمُ",
        "answer": "(is the) Day",
        "pcklId": "319",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmu",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ مَا أَدْرَاكَ مَا يَوْمُ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(The) Day",
        "pcklId": "320",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ لَا تَمْلِكُ نَفْسٌ لِنَفْسٍ شَيْئًا وَالْأَمْرُ يَوْمَئِذٍ لِلَّهِ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(on the) Day",
        "pcklId": "400",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "82",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " يَصْلَوْنَهَا يَوْمَ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    }
]; 
export default words;